AZRAA FATHIMA

TALENT ACQUISITION SPECIALIST

Sembakkam, Chennai 600073 DOB: 20-Apr-1990 +91 9940050343 azraafathima.a.t@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Experienced Talent Acquisition Specialist with a demonstrated history of working in the Video and Telecom industry. Skilled in Global recruitment, Campus recruitment, Technical recruitment, Sourcing, Contract Recruitment. Strong human resources professional with a Master's degree focused in Human Resource from St.Joseph's College Of Engineering with university ranking.

WORK EXPERIENCE

VELOCIX SOLUTIONS INDIA LLP (SPIN-OFF FROM NOKIA)

Talent Acquisition Specialist | Chennai | Jun 2017 - Mar 2023

- Handling recruitment activities for Velocix globally.
- Taking ownership of all inbound job applications for all roles.
- Screening candidates for talented professionals in Content Delivery networks for across the organisation in various locations Chennai, US, UK and Portugal.
- Being the first point of contact for agencies and external partners.
- Publishing jobs on Company website, Joboards like LinkedIn, Jobteaser.com(Portugal), Naukri, Hirist, Monster,
- Keeping an applicant tracking up-to date.
- Presenting the hiring activites to the Leadership team.
- $\bullet \ \ {\sf Employee Engagement\text{-}Coffee Meeting, Fun-activites \,, Games/Sports, High\text{-}Tea.}$

NOKIA (ALCATEL-LUCENT)

HR Executive | Chennai | Apr 2015 - Apr 2017

- Managing the Full Cycle recruitment process for Nokia from sourcing, screening, scheduling, selection, negotiation, various approvals, offers to post offer follow ups for Wire line & Wireless product groups at various levels & grades.
- Responsible to understand and analyze the requirements in different skill set categories. Managing & coordinating the entire recruitment process right from the manpower requisition till final placement.
- Concentrating on effective networking methods to reach the greatest number of potential candidates through internet sourcing, screening, direct mailing, LinkedIn, industry leads & sources, key contacts, portals, etc.
- Partner with Managers and BU/PU Director to assess and provide technical phone screens for a large volume of candidates and provided evaluations and recommendations for open requisitions.
- Building pipeline for technical positions to achieve targets as required by the business units
- Daily, Weekly and Monthly updates and reviews with Supervisors and the Management
- Actively endorse the Employee Referral Program, Campus and Off-Campus hiring and other low-cost hiring sources.
- · Managing database for all recruitment activities.
- Adequate knowledge and hands on experience in Taleo.
- Handled initial rounds (Aptitude Test) of interview & the final round of HR interview. Stake holder Management
- · Vendor Management.

EDUCATION

Master's Degree In The Field Of Human Resource And Finance (With University Ranking)

St Joseph's College Of Engineering, Chennai Jul 2012 - May 2014

Bachelor Of Engineering In Electronics And Communication Engineering.

Dhaanish Ahmed College of Engineering, Chennai Jul 2007 - May 2011

SKILLS

Office ,Excel, Power-Point

Technical Recruitment, Campus Hiring, Employee-Engagement

LANGUAGES

English (C2)

Hindi (B2)

Urdu (B2)

Tamil (B2)

HOBBIES







Travelling

Table tennis

Cooking



Badminton

PERSONAL DETAILS

CERTIFICATIONS

 Successfully completed HR Training Course i.e. Get Set...Go with Bridge HR Consulting PVT LTD

Gender

Female

Marital Status

Married

Nationality

Indian

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Gold Award towards unwavering commitment to Recruitment and working long hours and weekends at Velocix.
- Appreciation from technical managers on quick closures.
- Special appreciation from Global Director for closing the challenging position in 1 weeks time.